The Governor wins again
大都督又胜一筹
It seems you are going to lose today
看来 你今天要输了
That's not necessarily the case
那倒未必
Concubine Xiao wins again
萧妃娘娘再胜一筹
all right
可以呀
Come and play again
来 再来一局
good
好
Grand Governor
大都督
Food is lost
粮丢了
The city was also lost
城也丢了
I didn’t expect Guo Zhi to be so useless.
没想到郭直这么不顶用
This is Li Ni, the grandson of the Seventeenth Emperor
这个十七皇孙李嶷
Quite a bit
还真有点
Let people treat their descendants of the Li family
让人对他们李家的子孙
impressed
刮目相看
The old slave deserves to die
老奴该死
Dirty the governor's balls
污了大都督的球
Call Liang Wang
叫梁王来
yes
是
Biography of King Liang
传梁王
I met the great governor
见 见过大 大都督
Help the king of Liang get up
搀梁王起来
you are a prince
你是个王爵
I'm just a governor
我只是个都督
Why do you see me every time
怎么每次见到我
You have to give such a big gift.
都要行这么大的礼啊
Princess Tai
太公主
Xiao Wang pays homage to the Crown Princess
小王拜见太子妃
The first prince was foolish and ignorant
先太子昏庸无道
I have already committed suicide to thank the world
早已自裁以谢天下
I am no longer a princess.
妾身早就不是太子妃了
I also look forward to the future of King Liang
还望梁王以后
Don’t compare it to this
莫以此相称
Yes Yes Yes
是 是 是
Concubine Xiao
萧妃娘娘
Tell us about your son
说说你的儿子吧
This was asked by the great governor
这 蒙大都督垂问
Xiao Wang has three sons
小王有三子
eldest son Li
长子李
Who wants to listen to this nonsense?
谁要听这些乱七八糟的
Let’s talk about Li Yi
说说李嶷
just just
只是 只是
Seventeenth Seventeenth Lang Li Yita
十七 十七郎李嶷他
What's up with him
他怎么了
King Liang, do you know your guilt?
梁王 你可知罪
two months ago
两个月前
Pei Xian and others actually served Li Ni
裴献等人竟奉李嶷
For the so-called counterinsurgency marshal
为所谓的平叛元帅
A young Li Ni
一个乳臭未干的李嶷
Being defeated by a rebel general like Pei Xian
被裴献这种逆军大将
Become the commander
奉为主帅
Liang Wang
梁王
You are doing this in secret
你这是在暗中
Are you coveting a big position?
觊觎大位吗
This this
这 这
rude to children
小儿无礼
Child is rude
小儿无礼呀
this
这
Xiao Wang really doesn’t know this
小王是真不知道这
This Li Yi
这个李嶷
To be able to do such a thing
竟然能干出这等事来
I really don't know
我真是不知道
Seek guidance from the Governor
求大都督明鉴
okay
行了
This is Pei Xian
这也就是裴献
Demagoguery
蛊惑人心的伎俩
Just tell me honestly
你就老老实实地说说
Your son
你这个儿子
What did you like growing up?
从小喜欢什么
don't like what
不喜欢什么
What is your personality and temper like?
性格脾气是什么样子的
Xiao Wang’s son
小王的这个儿子
What an ominous son!
真是不祥之子啊
seventeen
十七
Li Yi was born
李嶷一出生
He killed his biological mother
就克死了他的生母
He has been naughty since childhood
他从小顽劣不堪
Unlearned and incompetent
不学无术
I am a father
我这个做父亲的
He also neglected to discipline him
也对他疏于管教
give me back
还给我
The maid gives birth to a son
婢生子
Your mother is the humblest slave
你娘是最卑微的奴婢
give me back
还给我
sooner or later one day
迟早有一天
You will kill us
你会克死我们的
give me back
还给我
Wait until he is older
待他年纪稍长
Even more idle
更是游手好闲
Fighting and causing trouble
打架闹事
This matter today
今天这个事情
You have to give me an explanation
你必须给我个交代
otherwise
否则
What are you doing?
你们干什么 干什么
Breech baby
臀位宝宝
stand up
起来
Xiao Wang’s son
小王的这儿子
Really naughty
实在是顽劣不堪
Extremely badass
混账至极
What a bastard
混账至极呀
Just because he is like this
正因为他这样
father emperor
父皇
No
不
The late emperor was furious
先帝震怒
Demoted him to Zhenxi Army
把他贬到镇西军中去了
But Xiao Wang never expected
可是小王万万没想到
He is so bold
他居然这么胆大包天
This this
这 这
What kind of marshal do you dare to call yourself?
敢自称什么元帅
Against the Governor
与大都督作对
It’s true that an evil moon gives birth to an evil son
真是恶月生恶子
Li Yi is still young now
李嶷现在尚还年纪轻轻
You can use this trick to occupy my Wangzhou
就能出此诡计占我望州
It's really unworthy
果然是不肖
Not worth it enough
足够不值得
people like you
像你这样的人
How can it be born
怎么能生得出
Like Li Yi
像李嶷这样的
The gifted son
天纵英才的儿子
Lift it down
抬下去
yes
是
This time we got a bargain
这次咱们捡了一个便宜
Occupied Wangzhou City
占了望州城
But Guo Zhi's army was not damaged
但是郭直的大军未损
Moreover, the merger of states and the establishment of states
而且并州和建州
In the hands of Han Li again
又在韩立的手中
I'm just afraid that Sun Jing will send Han Li to send troops
只怕孙靖会派韩立出兵
He and Guo Zhi attacked us from both sides.
和郭直前后夹击咱们
Then we will capture Wangzhou first
那我们就先夺望州
Another plan to merge the states
再图并州
you guess
你猜
What are the Cui family doing now?
崔家的人现在在做什么
Cui family
崔家
We're right under their noses
我们在他们眼皮子底下
Picked up Wangzhou City
捡了望州城
Such a big one is cheap
这么大一个便宜
Cui Yi's only son personally led the troops
崔倚独子亲自带兵
Raising troops and mobilizing people but returning in vain
兴师动众 徒劳而返
You'll definitely be furious
一定会气急败坏
you mean
你是说
Guo Zhi's army hangs alone outside the city
郭直大军孤悬城外
No city to occupy, no food to eat
无城可据 无粮可食
If I were from the Cui family
我要是崔家的人
I will definitely send someone
我定会派一个人
Go to Guo Zhijun for peace talks
去郭直军中和谈
Encircle and attack him
与他来个合围夹击
Capture Wangzhou City in one fell swoop
一举拿下望州城
kick me out
踢我出局
I don't allow you to go
我不许你去
Young Master
公子
The two armies are fighting without killing the envoy
两军交战 不斩来使
As the envoy of Cui Jiajun, I
我作为崔家军的使节
Go to
前往
Guo Zhi, he can’t
郭直他不会
What to do to me
把我怎么样的
Aying
阿萤
I don't want you to be in danger again
我不希望你再涉险
Young Master
公子
you guess
你猜猜
At this moment, the people in the Zhenxi Army
此刻镇西军中的人
doing what
在做什么
If I were in the Zhenxi Army
我要是镇西军中的人
knowing that
明知道
It was Cui Jiajun who stole the food and grass
是崔家军抢了粮草
Now I know
现在又知道
Guo Zhi hangs alone outside the city
郭直孤悬城外
No food to eat, no city to occupy
无粮可食 无城可据
I definitely want to go to Guo Zhijun Middle School
肯定想着去郭直军中
Make peace with him
与他和谈
give him benefits
给他好处
Discuss with him to encircle together
再跟他商量一起合围
Attack our Cui Jiajun from both sides
夹击我们崔家军
So that I can get my food back
好夺回粮草
Then let's strike first
那咱就来个先下手为强
no no no
不不不
The plank road was repaired in the open, but Chencang was buried in the dark
明修栈道 暗度陈仓
I went out of the city to have peace talks with Guo Zhi
我出城与郭直和谈
When I get to Guo Zhijun,
待我到了郭直军中
The Cui family will naturally consider it
崔家人自然会考量一下
Is it a good deal to be my enemy?
到底是与我为敌划算呢
You'd better form an alliance with me first
还是与我先结盟
It's a good deal to deal with Guo Zhi
收拾了郭直划算
Then how do you know
那你怎么知道
Someone named Cui will definitely send someone
姓崔的一定会派人
Are you negotiating with Guo Zhi?
和郭直谈判呢
Since the war
自战乱一起
Cui Yi was ambitious
崔倚就野心勃勃地
Send an army south
派大军南下
It can be seen that he never misses an opportunity.
可见是一个绝不失机的
smart people
聪明人
Such a big piece of cake
这么一大块饼
Will he let it go?
他会放过吗
I'm planning to
我打算
The plank road was repaired in the open, but Chencang was buried in the dark
明修栈道 暗度陈仓
Wait until I get to Guo Zhi's army
等我到了郭直的军中
Presumably the Zhenxi Army
想必那镇西军
Important people will definitely be sent out
也定然会派出要紧人物
I guess
我猜测
Eighty percent of it is the one named Pei
八成是那个姓裴的
come forward in person
亲自出面
Waiting to borrow Guo Zhi's territory
等借了郭直的地盘
I will talk to the people from the Zhenxi Army again
我再和镇西军的人
The interview is
面谈就是
But according to what you said
但据你所言
Isn't the other party very difficult to deal with?
对方不是难缠得很吗
That’s why I want to borrow Guo Zhi’s territory
所以才要借郭直的地盘
To show sincerity
对方为显诚意
I'm sure I'll only bring my personal guards with me.
肯定也是只带亲卫
By the time
到时候
Surrounded by Guo Zhi's army
有郭直大军环绕
Even if he wants to play some tricks
即便他想耍什么花样
It’s also difficult to cast
也很难施展
But I think
但是我觉得
Still too dangerous
还是太危险了
You defend the city
你据守城池
I went out of the city to talk to Guo Zhi
我出城 和郭直谈
Of course General Pei is going.
当然是小裴将军去啊
And me
我呢
Just write a handwritten letter at home
就在家里写一封手书
Print again
再印上
The seal of our counterinsurgent marshal
我们平叛元帅的大印
to show our sincerity
以示我们的诚意
I plan to use you as a carrot again
又打算拿你这个萝卜
Carve one yourself
自己刻一个呀
Anyway, Guo Zhi and the Cui family
反正郭直和崔家人
never seen me
没有见过我
handsome seal
的帅印
It turned out to be He Xiaowei from Cui Jiajun
原来是崔家军的何校尉
first meet
初次见面
Nice to meet you
幸会幸会
It turned out to be from the Zhenxi Army
原来是镇西军的
General Pei
小裴将军
Your Majesty, General Pei
令尊裴将军
Guarding the border for many years
镇守边陲多年
prestigious
威名赫赫
Admire for a long time
久仰久仰
Both are young talents
两位都是少年才俊
Today is an eye-opener for Guo
今日令郭某大开眼界
General Pei personally came to discuss peace
小裴将军亲自前来议和
Cui Gongzi sent He Xiaowei
崔公子遣何校尉
Also come to discuss peace
亦来议和
Guo was really flattered
郭某真是受宠若惊
Sincerely fearful
诚惶诚恐
Afraid of letting down
既怕辜负了
Some kind words from General Pei
小裴将军的一番美意
And I was afraid of displeasing Mr. Cui
又怕令崔公子不悦
It's really difficult for me
在下实在是难为得很哪
General Guo is a heretic
郭将军外道了
General Guo is polite.
郭将军客气了
How about this?
不如这样吧
Each of our three parties will send one person
咱们三方各遣一人
Have a horse race
来一场赛马
If my people win
若是我的人赢了
Please two
请二位
Everyone agrees to a condition
各答应我一个条件
If there are two people, who will win?
若是二位的人谁赢了
Then who should I talk to first?
那我就先和谁谈
I don’t know what you two think
不知二位意下如何
very fair
公平得很
Since General Pei is so generous,
既然小裴将军这么大方
Of course I have nothing to say
我自然也并无二话
good
好
Both of them are cheerful people
两位都是爽快之人
please
请
general
将军
go all out
全力以赴
yes
是
long ears
长耳
Be cautious
小心谨慎
yes
是
You are a good horse
你这匹马不错
Your horse is pretty good too
你那匹也不错啊
General Pei deserves the award.
小裴将军过奖了
That little General Pei thinks
那小裴将军觉得
Who will be the final winner?
谁会是最后的赢家呢
Never tried
未曾比试
Who knows who will win?
焉知鹿死谁手啊
General Pei
小裴将军
Have you ever met Captain He before?
之前可曾识得何校尉
Never
不曾
Your Majesty
令尊当年
Seriously injured at Huya Pass
在虎牙关受过重伤
Later every time it rained
后来每逢阴雨
Old injuries will recur
便会旧伤发作
unbearable soreness
酸痛难忍
I wonder if it has been better in recent years
不知近些年可曾好些
Thank you General for your greetings
多谢将军问候
My father suffered from many old wounds
家父所受旧伤有数处
The arrow wound under the ribs is the most dangerous
肋下那道箭伤最为凶险
Although so many years
虽然这么多年
Always in the military
一直在军中
But take good care of it
但是悉心调养
Already much better
已经好得多了
That's good
如此便好
No limit to weapons
不限兵刃
Click till then
点到为止
Don't hurt your life
勿伤性命
after capture the flag
夺旗之后
Who returns here first
谁先返回此处
Insert the small flag into this circle
将小旗插入此圈
is the winner
是赢家
Set off
出发
Lieutenant He's bodyguards are really powerful
何校尉的亲卫果然厉害
It seems that this round
看来这一局
Captain He is going to win
是何校尉要胜出了
where
哪里
This person
此人
They are the bodyguards of our Mr. Cui.
乃是我们崔公子的亲卫
The young master sent me as an envoy
公子派我出使
He was specially sent to take care of one or two
特意派遣他来照拂一二
Moreover
再说了
The end has not yet come
终局未至
How can we talk about winning or losing lightly?
岂能轻言输赢呢
brothers brothers
兄弟 兄弟
wake up
醒醒
brother
兄弟
Wake up
醒醒啊
brothers brothers
兄弟 兄弟
brother
兄弟
Comrades
同袍
brothers brothers
兄弟 兄弟
brother
兄弟
Comrades
同袍
I made a mistake
是我失手了
With the skill of this strong soldier just now,
以刚刚这位健卒的身手
You can completely avoid that arrow
完全可以避开那一箭
He is eager to win
他求胜心切
So I never dodge
所以不曾闪避
This person is loyal and brave
此人忠勇
We admire
令我等钦佩
The general wins now
现在是将军赢了
According to the preface
依照前言
Me and Cui Jiajun
我和崔家军
Each agrees to a condition for the general
各答应将军一个条件
Please also ask General Guo to speak frankly.
还请郭将军直言
It's getting late today
今日天色已晚
I will continue to work for this comrade
我等还要为这位同袍
buried
归葬
I'm so sad right now
我此刻哀痛心乱
Two more please
还请二位
Stay in camp tonight
今晚就留在营中
Let’s talk tomorrow
等明日再谈
But according to the general's orders
但凭将军吩咐
General's condolences
将军节哀
general
将军
today
今天
Although I lost my comrades in the army,
虽然折损了军中同袍
a life
一条性命
but always win
但总是赢了
The general feels
将军觉得
Let the two of them be together tomorrow
明日让他们两家
What conditions can we agree to?
答应我们什么条件才好
Pei Yuan is in crisis
裴源于危急中
Instead, he rescued Captain He
反而救助了何校尉
both of them
他们双方
It is clear that friends outweigh enemies
分明就是友大于敌
Just in case the two of them have other plans
万一两人另有图谋
Just afraid
只怕
They agreed to our terms
他们答应我们的条件
It's all just a trap
都不过是陷阱
today
今天
I must kill these two people
我必要诛杀此二人
in front of the governor
在大都督面前
With the heads of these two people
有了此二人的人头
Even if we lose our city and food
哪怕是失城失粮
You can also explain it to me
也都能交代过去
What does the general mean?
那将军的意思是
Last time Dr. Fan
上次范军医
It’s not like we made a lot of them
不是制作了好多
Special pastries?
特制的糕点吗
You go get two copies
你去取两份
Find two smart people
找两个机灵的人
Send one to each of them
给他们一人送一份
This healthy soldier
这位健卒
really one
真的是一位
A rare brave man
难得的忠勇之士
No wonder General Guo thinks so highly of him
难怪郭将军这么器重他
Hold his funeral in person
亲自为他举办葬礼
Then the people from Cui Jiajun now
那现在崔家军的人
I must regret it very much
肯定十分后悔
they missed
他们失手
General Guo lost a comrade
让郭将军损失一位同袍
Peace talks tomorrow
明日和谈
They have lost the initiative
他们未免失了主动
of course not
当然不会
They were not originally
他们本来就不是
Came to talk to Guo Zhi
来和郭直谈的
This Colonel He has always been cunning
这个何校尉素来狡诈
You won't suffer for sure
肯定不会吃亏
So what should we do now
那我们现在怎么办
Of course go
当然是去
Let’s meet Captain He for a while.
会一会这个何校尉了
Oops
糟糕
midnight
三更半夜
General Pei
小裴将军
It was the last time I took a bath in the well
是上次在井里洗澡
Very comfortable to wash
洗得太舒服
So you came to me specially
所以特地来找我
A well of grace
一井之恩
Never forget
永世难忘
Remember next time
在下时刻记得
girl's kindness
姑娘的恩德
Don't think I don't know
别以为我不知道
I think about you all the time
你时时刻刻都惦记着
Kick me in anytime
随时把我也踹进
In that well
那个井里
Good to pay back the grudge of that well
好还那一井之仇
right
对不对
no problem
没问题啊
I am waiting
我等着
Return the property to its original owner
物归原主
Thank you very much
多谢了
you woman
你这个女人
Why are you so rude?
怎么这么无礼啊
Then you stole my beads?
那你抢走我的珠子呢
Why don't you return the property to its original owner?
怎么不物归原主啊
You took my things
你抢走我的东西
I'll get it back based on my ability
我凭本事拿回来
I take your stuff
我拿走你的东西
You can still do it
你照样也可以
Take it back based on your ability
凭本事拿回去啊
He Xiaowei
何校尉
What happened so late at night?
大晚上的 怎么了
Our General Guo said
我们郭将军言道
There was supposed to be a banquet for guests tonight
今晚本该设宴款待宾客
But it was delayed due to something
但因事耽搁了
This army is extremely crude
这军中简陋至极
Really poor hospitality
实在招待不周
I was specially ordered to deliver this snack
特命我送来这份点心
Give He Xiaowei some food
给何校尉垫饥
Thank you, General Guo Zhi
多谢郭直将军
Take the trouble
费心了
Oops
糟糕
You said you are a little girl?
你说你个小姑娘家
Don't do embroidery properly in the boudoir
不好好在闺阁里绣花
He wants to get involved in military matters
偏要掺和军中的事
Just come if you come
你来就来吧
Still plotting against me at every turn
还动不动暗算我
you say
你说
I'm going to carry you now
我现在是要把你扛起来
Throw it into the well
扔到井里去
Let you try it
还是让你尝尝
This crossbow is powerful
这弩的厉害
want to talk
想要说话
Then you say it
那你说吧
Can't say
说不了
There are walnuts in your mouth, right?
嘴里有核桃对不对
It's not impossible to talk if you want to
想说话也不是不行
But let’s talk first
不过先说好
If I put the walnuts in your mouth
我要是把你嘴里的核桃
take it out
拿出来
If you want to yell
你要大喊大叫的话
I'll let you taste it
我就让你尝一下
Your Cui family crossbow is very powerful
你们崔家弩的厉害
There are organs in the mouth
嘴里还有机关
Is this needle poisonous?
这针上面是不是有毒啊
If you are not honest again
你要再不老实
I'll prick you with a needle
我就拿针扎你
Where are so many needles?
这么多针哪
Such a delicate thing
这么精致的东西
Gave it to me
送我了
Why are you not convinced?
看什么 不服气啊
Stab you
扎你啊
Just wait for me
你给我等着
you two
你们二人
Lead a small group of troops respectively
分别带一小队人马
Send someone to inquire first
先派人去打探
What is their condition?
他们到底是何状况
If they had a snack
若他们吃了点心
Already unconscious
已然昏迷
That would be the best
那便再好不过
If they haven't been poisoned yet
若他们尚未中毒
Get started now
即刻动手
yes
是
Laolan River Eighteen Bays
牢兰河水十八湾
General Pei
小裴将军
Come to Guo Zhi's army
到这郭直大军中来
Probably not sincere
想必也不是真心
I want to have peace talks with Guo Zhi
想和郭直和谈
But he has other plans
而是另有所谋
That being the case
既然如此
why not
为何就不能
Open the skylight and speak frankly.
打开天窗说亮话呢
Captain He is indeed a smart man
何校尉果然是个聪明人
only
只不过
Who are you from the Cui family?
你到底是崔家什么人
Do you mean what you say?
说话作数吗
Little General Pei can take charge of things
小裴将军能做主的事
I can make the decision
我都能做主
That's not a bad tone
口气不小啊
What's going on with your Cui family?
你们崔家的事
You can do it for Mr. Cui
你都能替你们崔公子
Make the decision
做主啊
It will be all right
都可以
There's a fire
起火啦
It's bad to catch fire
起火啦 不好啦
It's on fire. It's on fire. It's on fire.
起火了 起火了 起火了
quick
快
You should untie me first
你倒是先把我解开啊
What did you deploy in advance?
你事先部署了什么
What else did you deploy?
你又部署了什么
You are so scheming
你真是诡计多端啊
each other
彼此彼此啊
what are you doing
你干什么
kick
踹
It's not good. It's not good.
不好了 不好了
The Zhenxi Army attacked the camp
镇西军袭营了
quick
快
Quickly
快 快
It's not good. It's not good.
不好了 不好了
Attacked the camp
袭营了
The Zhenxi Army attacked the camp
镇西军袭营了
Zhenxi Army Attacks Camp
镇西军袭营
Who framed us among these people?
这帮东西 谁栽赃我们
Bring more water
再拿水来
Put out the fire quickly
快灭火
Thank you very much
多谢啊
how do you know
你怎么知道
i can kill them
我可以杀掉他们
You are so scheming
你这么诡计多端的
one person
一个人
Don’t hide it on your body
身上不藏个
Eight murder weapons out of ten
十件八件杀器
I'm afraid I'll underestimate you
我都怕我小看你
Laolan River Eighteen Bays
牢兰河水十八湾
It's fun to set fire to it
放火放得蛮开心嘛
I watched you shoot an arrow
我看你放箭
It's quite fun to let it go.
放得也挺开心的嘛
Then don't bother me
那就不打扰了
Go on
你继续
You keep going
你继续 继续
What is your plan?
你到底什么计划
I have no plan
我没计划
I will follow you as you go
你怎么走我跟你怎么走
You don't know how to draw a horse
你不会连马
Not even prepared?
都没有准备吧
I thought you were ready
我以为你准备了
Why are you so shameless?
你这人怎么那么无耻啊
I just found out today
今天才知道啊
It's too late
已经晚了
Walk
走
Be careful, the rocket is coming again
小心 火箭又来了
careful
小心
quick
快
my people
我的人
You go back immediately
你现在立刻回去
Tell Pei Yuan
告诉裴源
things have changed
事情有变
Ask him to be sure to prevent Guo Zhi
让他务必防止郭直
and Cui Jiajun
和崔家军
Take advantage of the chaos to sneak attack on our Wangzhou City
趁乱偷袭我们望州城
If Wangzhou City is lost
如果望州城有失
Bingzhou City raised troops to attack again
并州城再举兵夹击
We will be passive
我们会很被动
Seventeen Lang, what about you?
十七郎 那你呢
Food is in their hands
粮食在他们手上
I'll go after food
我去追粮
quick
快
I knew you would be fooled
就知道你会上当
you just said
你刚才说
It's the captain who ordered you to come back and report the news
是校尉命你回来报讯
yes
是
Ashu was derelict in his duty
阿恕失职
I've been running from pursuers
我一直在躲避追兵
After escaping
脱身之后
Just came straight to the camp
才直奔营地而来
The captain said she would return to the camp after escaping.
校尉说她脱身就回营
Sir, please follow the original plan
请公子按原计划
Lead the army to attack Wangzhou
率军进攻望州
Send an order
传令
strike camp
拔营
The army went all out to search for Lieutenant He
大军全力搜索何校尉
Young Master
公子
The captain said
校尉说过
Wangzhou City is now on an unstable footing.
望州城此时立足不稳
leaderless
群龙无首
Just the right opportunity
正是可取之机
Did the young master follow the original plan?
公子是否按原定之计
Lead an army to attack Wangzhou
率大军进攻望州
If it is because of the attack on Wangzhou
若是因为进攻望州
wasted the opportunity
耽搁了时机
Did the captain make any mistakes?
校尉有任何闪失
I will only regret it
我只会追悔莫及
Young Master
公子
Since the captain has arranged it like this
校尉既如此安排
There must be some certainty
定有几分把握
Just pretend it's nothing
想来自当无事
Ashu
阿恕
You don't have to persuade me anymore
你不必再劝我了
Send an order
传令
Break camp immediately
即刻拔营
yes
是
Don't be in a hurry and eat slowly
不着急 慢慢吃
It's okay, General Pei
没事 小裴将军
I am full
我已经吃饱了
Seventeen Lang emphasized again and again
十七郎再三强调
Let you be careful
让你一定要提防
Cui Jiajun and Guo Zhi
崔家军和郭直
Take advantage of the chaos to attack Wangzhou City
趁乱进攻望州城
Then I'll leave the city first
那我先出城
Go and pick up Shichiro
去接应十七郎
OK
行
When you meet Shichiro
你见着十七郎的时候
tell him
告诉他
reassure him
让他放心
I will definitely think of something
我定会想法子
To protect Wangzhou City
保住望州城的
good
好
You're not going in that direction
你不是朝那个方向
Did you chase him?
追过去了吗
I am a person who has a clear distinction between grudges and grudges.
我这个人很恩怨分明的
an eye for an eye
有仇必报
Bastard
浑蛋
Last time you kicked me into a well
上次你把我踹到井里
I didn't even scold you.
我都没骂你呢
Help
救命
Okay, little liar
行了 小骗子
have you forgotten
你是不是忘了
when we first met
我们第一次见面的时候
It's in the water
就在水里啊
You are very good at water, I remember
你水性很好 我记得
My legs are cramped
我腿抽筋了
Help
救命
Someone like you
你这样的人啊
You should learn a lesson
就该受点教训
Help
救命
little liar
小骗子
What if you don’t come out again?
你要是再不出来呢
I'll take your horse away
我可就把你的马牵走了
I'm really gone
我真走了
wake up wake up
醒醒 醒醒
call me little liar
叫我小骗子
And kicked me into the river
还把我踹到河里
I won't call you today
今天不叫你
Go and take a dip in the cold water in this river
去这河里泡泡冷水
You call me a little liar in vain
枉你叫我小骗子
never mind
算了
See if you go to the river
看在你去河里
For saving my sake
救我的份儿上
Let me help you one more time
我再帮你一次吧
To prevent the pursuers from coming over
免得那些追兵过来
I'll cut you off with one knife
一刀把你给砍了
Xiaobai, run quickly
小白 快跑
Xiaobai, go quickly
小白 快走
Go back and find someone
回去找人来
so hungry
好饿呀
I didn’t bring any dry food with me either.
也没带干粮出来
What a mistake
真是失策
Do you want to eat rabbit meat?
兔肉吃不吃啊
It's you
是你
yes it's me
是啊 是我
The anesthetic on your needle
你那针上的麻药
Really awesome
可真厉害
Let me sleep until late and then wake up
让我睡到天晚时分才醒
I'll take a look when I wake up
我这醒来一看
The horse is gone too
马也没了
You ran away too
你也跑了
You said I worked so hard
你说我这辛辛苦苦
I walked for more than two hours
走了两个多时辰的路
walk here
走到这儿
God has eyes
老天有眼
Let me meet you here
让我在这儿遇到了你
I knew it
我就知道
You are such a vicious person
是你这样歹毒的人
Only then could such a trap be designed.
才设计得出这样的陷阱
You are too good at wronging me, right?
你也太会冤枉我了吧
This is obviously a hunter hunting a bear
这明明就是猎人猎熊
hunting hole
用的猎洞
Look how deep the hole is dug
你看这洞挖得这么深
You know it’s not a day’s work
就知道非一日之功了
Did you see a wasp just now?
你刚才还看到马蜂了吧
So what
是又怎么样
Isn't this right?
这不就对了
There are many bears in this mountain
这山间熊多
bear skin bear bile bear paw
熊皮 熊胆 熊掌
All are rare treasures
皆是奇珍
Can be sold at a high price
能卖个高价钱
But hunting bears is extremely difficult
但猎熊极难
But what about the bear?
不过熊呢
Love to eat mountain honey again
又爱吃山蜜
So hunters are generally
所以猎人一般
Will choose a place with honeycombs
会挑有蜂窝的地方
Set up such a trap
设置这样的陷阱
It's just that the hunter didn't think of it
只是猎人没有想到
I haven't hunted this bear yet.
这熊嘛 没猎到
Little liar caught
小骗子 落网一头
It smells so good
真香啊
How about we make a deal?
那咱们做个交易怎么样
And me
我呢
Please eat rabbit legs
请你吃兔腿
And you
你呢
Give me back the rations
把军粮还给我
What do you mean by returning the military rations to you?
什么叫把军粮还给你啊
That was obviously my trick
那明明是我用计
Earned military rations
赚来的军粮
It smells so good
真香啊
So delicious
好好吃啊
How about I make a deal with you?
我跟你做个交易怎么样
Where's the rabbit?
兔子呢
There are four legs in total
一共有四条腿
You won't let me put these four legs
你不会让我把这四条腿
Eat them all
都吃了吧
He Xiaowei
何校尉
You have been there day and night
你已经一天一夜
Nothing to eat
没有吃东西了
When I just roasted this rabbit
我刚烤这兔子的时候啊
The sizzling meat is dripping with oil.
滋滋的那个肉直冒油啊
Do you know how fragrant it is?
你知道有多香吗
Tell you
告诉你啊
As long as you give me the military rations quickly
只要你赶紧把军粮给我
And me
我呢
I'll treat you to rabbit meat
就请你吃兔肉
OK
行
Since we want to talk
既然要谈
There has to be some sincerity.
总得有点诚意吧
You rescue me first
你先救我上去
Then I gave the army rations
然后我就把军粮
Give you half
分你一半
But this half of the army rations
不过这一半军粮
I have to wait until you escort me there
也要等到你把我护送到
After Cui Jiajun’s camp
崔家军大营之后
I can give it to you
我才能给你
you little liar
你这个小骗子
You think I'm a little fool, right?
把我当成小傻瓜了是吧
Say it
说吧
How many of those bamboo tubes do you have on your body?
身上还有多少那种竹筒
How many of those poisonous needles are there?
多少根那种毒针啊
Why are you scared?
怎么 害怕了
Then don't save me from going out
那你别救我出去好了
You go
你走吧
Let me die here alone
让我一个人死在这儿
Your military rations are gone too
你的军粮也没了
look back
回头
Waiting for our young master
等我们家公子
know about my death
知道我的死讯
Will definitely be angry
也一定会震怒
He will come to avenge me
他会来替我报仇的
OK
行
That being the case
既然如此
Then I will come down to accompany you
那我就下来陪你了
you are crazy
你疯了
I'm the only one in there
就我一个人在里面
Can you still save me?
你还能救我上去
Now you come down too
现在你也下来
How do we two get up there?
我们俩怎么上去啊
Thanks to you
托你的福
I've been in the well too
井里我也待过了
I've been in the river too
河里我也待过了
You said we are so destined
你说咱们这么有缘分
You've all fallen into a trap
你都掉陷阱里了
Can I come down?
我能不下来
Will I live and die with you?
陪你同生共死吗
Frivolous and dissolute
轻薄浪荡
You scolded me twice today
你今天一天骂我两回了
I'm a very vindictive person
我这个人很记仇的
I originally wanted to give it to you
我本来想给你
Two rabbit legs
两条兔腿的
But you scolded me once
但你骂我一次
I'll give you one less
我少给你一条
You scolded me twice today
你今天骂我两次
You haven't eaten a single thing
你一条都没的吃
You can only watch me eat
只能看我吃
So fragrant
真香
me
我这个人
Very clear-cut
很恩怨分明的
Even though you stung me with a needle and knocked me out
虽然你拿针刺晕了我
But before you leave
但你临走前
He piled straw on me out of kindness
好心在我身上堆了堆草
One yard owned by a yard
一码归一码
hurry up
快点
how about my craft
怎么样 我的手艺
It's well roasted
是烤得不错
Can you
你能不能
tell me honestly
老老实实告诉我
How on earth are we two going to get there?
咱们俩到底怎么上去
how do you know
你怎么知道
I have a way to get up there
我有办法上去啊
Even though I’ve known you not long ago
虽然跟你认识不久
But you are a cunning person
但你这为人 阴险狡诈
How can you do something that is impossible to do?
岂会行毫无办法之事
Since you can come down
你既然能够下来
There must be a way to get up there
就肯定有办法能上去
You think so highly of me
你这样对我评价挺高的
You said so
你都这么说了
Let me tell you the truth
实话告诉你吧
Where am I tonight?
我今晚呢
Not planning to go up
不打算上去
What
什么
It’s all so dark
都这么黑了
This deep mountain and dense forest
这深山密林的
Who knows except the bear
谁知道除了熊
What other beasts are there?
还有什么猛兽啊
Suddenly another one
突然再来个
Tigers, leopards, etc.
老虎 豹子什么的
Wouldn't that be all over?
那不就全完了吗
I know
我知道
You have powder on you
你身上有药粉
Snakes and ants do not invade
蛇蚁不侵
But those beasts
但那些猛兽
I'm not afraid of your powder
可不怕你的药粉
so what
所以呢
listen to me
听我说
Just take a nap here
乖乖在这里睡上一觉
Tomorrow morning
明天一早
I shall take Captain He hostage
我自当挟持何校尉
Go to your Cui family army in exchange for military rations
去你们崔家军换取军粮
Such a shameless trick
如此无耻伎俩
And he said it so confidently
还说得这样理直气壮
Don't we have each other?
我们不彼此彼此吗
somebody is coming
有人来了
You said it yourself
你自己说的
Wild beasts roaming deep in the mountains and forests
深山密林 野兽横行
Where did this person come from?
哪儿来的人
Quick, quick, quick, quick
快快快 快快快
Got it
有了
Hurry up
快快快
There must be good stuff
肯定有好货
that is
就是
Go quickly
快走
There must be good stuff
肯定有好货啊
Listen to me
听我的啊
Take a look at me
照照 我看看
what
什么呀
Come and see
来 我看
I can't see clearly, that's wrong
看不清啊 不对呀
How can this be a human being?
这 这怎么是人呢
It's two people
是两个人啊